(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Happy Birthday, Princess Sisters!
I'm Fuwawa!
I'm Mococo!
BAU BAU!
Nerissa Ravencroft
Koseki Bijou
Shiori Novella
Mori Calliope
Oozora Subaru
Ookami Mio
Aki Rosenthal
Shirakami Fubuki
AZKi
FUWAMOCO!
Ruffians! It's showtime!
It's showtime!
一緒にいたいよ
I want to be together
Lifetime, Showtime
Anytime, BAU BAU!
Yeah, future is bright
Fluffy, fuzzy, yappy sisters
Fuwa! Moco!
BAU BAU BAU!
FUWA!
MOCO!
BAU BAU BAU BAU!
My heart 'n' soul 'n' tail are FUWAWA (Yay!)
I'm so fluffy that even I could float away
Just call for me, we're only a bark away
Your smile is the treasure that I wanna keep safe
FUWA!
MOCO!
I love being tricky
Doggy kisses are for me
I love lots of walkies
Don't need no leashes for me
Silly puppy Mococo will follow you anywhere
FUWAMOCO together, take us along with you
Barking oh so merrily!
It's showtime!
一緒にいたいよ (Oh!)
I want to be together (Oh!)
Lifetime, Showtime
Anytime, BAU BAU!
一生涯 Sing with you
Sing with you for a lifetime
Stars wink
Moon spotlight
Furr-over glow
It's showtime!
一緒にいたいよ
I want to be together
Lifetime, Showtime
Anytime, BAU BAU!
Yeah, future is bright
Fluffy, fuzzy, yappy sisters
Way back then,
all locked up,
we were stuck in the cell
Holding back,
doggy dog kept sealed away
BAU!
Bouta burst,
fluff & fuzz
we're meant to be free
BAU!
Bouta burst, fluff & fuzz, we're meant to be free
Make a break for it, it's playtime!
I'm hitting the pavement, dreams sparklin' within our eyes
Gonna keep you smilin', but my seconds won't stop flyin' by
Even though we're still just a pair of scaredy puppy dogs
The bond that we share as twins is irreplaceable
We're a pair, unbreakable!
And that's why!
いつだって
Any time!
It's that day!
Today!
Lifetime! Showtime!
Not tomorrow! BAU BAU!
一生涯
For a lifetime,
Walk with you!
I'll walk with you!
Good times and bad times, it doesn't matter
いつだって
Any time!
It's that day!
Lifetime! Showtime!
Every day! BAU BAU!
Yeah, Yeah!
二人は
The two of us are...
Happy, lucky, puppy sisters!
FUWAMOCO! BAU! BAU!
Everybody, BAU! BAU!
Hallo, hallo! BAU! BAU!
ダメダメノンノン！
No-no, stop that!
Don't touch the ears!
もふもふノンノン！
No-no fluffy touching!
Don't touch the tail!
チワワじゃないよ！
It's not a chihuahua!
フワワだよ！
It's a Fuwawa!
チワワじゃないよ！
It's not a chihuahua!
モココだよ！
It's a Mococo!
Twin demon guard dog sisters, yeah! BAU!
And together, we're...
FUWAMOCO!
Gather up our dreams
And suddenly you'll come to realize
There's as many as there are stars
Illuminating the night sky
Never-ending dreams
We don't know if they all can be achieved
But we'll keep on going furr-ever
Together here with you!
It's showtime
一緒にいたい
I want to be with you
It's showtime 一緒にいたい
It's showtime, I want to be with you
It's showtime 一緒にいたいよ
Fuwa fuwa Moco moco hand in hand with you
Bring your smile, rain or shine
We'll protect it, won't forget our pledge to you!
It's showtime!
一緒にいたい
I want to be with you
Lifetime Showtime Anytime BAU BAU!
一生涯
For a lifetime,
Sing with you
I'll sing with you
Stars wink, moon spotlight, furr-ever glow
It's showtime!
一緒にいたいよ
I want to be with you
Lifetime Showtime Anytime BAU BAU!
And together we're
Fluffy fuzzy yappy sisters!
Let's hear you!
Sisters!
FUWA! MOCO! FUWA! MOCO!
Yeah! Yeah!
FUWA! FUWA! MOCO! MOCO!
FUWAMOCO BAU BAU! FUWAMOCO BAU BAU!
わっぴー！おっぴー！
Wappie! Oppie!
Welcome to our FUWAMOCO Wacha Wacha Birthday Festival!
わっぴー！おっぴー！
Wappie! Oppie!
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate our birthday with us!
わー！始まりました！わー！
Wow! It's started! Yay!
今日は生誕ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to our birthday live today!
Well, to continue off from yesterday's variety show,
tonight again, today we have a big concert!
And can you believe it? It's already been three years!
Right, our third birthday in Hololive!
Thank you! But Mococo-chan, we can't forget that really important thing, right?
Right?
Introductions!
Ah! Yeah! Okay!
I'm not a chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
I'm not Fuwawa, I'm Mococo!
We're Hololive English -Advent- twin demon guard dog sisters!
Together we're FUWAMOCO! Bau Bau!
わー！そしてモコちゃん、
Wow! And Moco-chan,
we have an amazing birthday festival stage here!
Amazing stage! Ruffians, so many of you!
And such a big Ruffian too!
Ah, Fuwawa! Can we?
Okay, shall we go?
3, 2, 1, Bau Bau!
It's so big and wide too!
Thank you for being here today!
But, singing and dancing today is not just gonna be us, right?
No, we're also here with some very special guests too!
そう！今日はとっても素敵なゲストさんも来てるから、
That's right! Since we have some very wonderful guests coming today,
ぜひ楽しみにしててください！
please stay tuned and look forward to it!
そして、もう一人、謎のゲストさんも...
And, there's one more mysterious guest...
誰かな？わっぴー！おっぴー！
I wonder who it is? Wappie! Oppie!
But, a birthday wouldn't be complete without this, right?
Right, something very important.
I think you know well, but...
Hashtag!
Yes, the birthday hashtag!
Right up here, you can see our birthday hashtag.
#FWMCbday26, that it is!
Please, please post your thoughts, take lots of photos, screenshots!
ぜひハッシュタグで感想呟いてください！写真もね！
Please tweet your thoughts with the hashtag! Photos too!
後でポチしに行くからね！わっぴー！おっぴー！
Because I'll go 'like' them later! Wappie! Oppie!
We'll check all your thoughts after the show! Yeah! Bau Bau!
Also!
We're gonna be having a special membership-only
concert right after this! So don't miss it, okay?
Yeah! Mm!
最後にはメン限のアンコールライブもありますので
Lastly, there will also be a membership-only...
ぜひ見に来てくださいね！
...encore live, so please come watch it!
Bau bau!
You know, it is a concert after all, right?
Should we get singing a little more, yeah?
Yeah!
Wow! For this next song...
I think we need a special guest for this, right?
Yeah! Mm! Okay!
Let's call her on together! Okay?
Calli-senpai!
Hey hey hey hey hey!
こんばんは、皆さん！ Bau bau!
Good evening, everyone! Bau bau!
Today only, I am also a dog.
Bau bau bau bau!
Shinigami dog!
Reaper dog!
Yeah! Happy birthday FuwaMoco!
Thank you for inviting me, I'm happy to be here.
What's up Ruffians?
But I see you have a pretty nice shirt there, huh?
I do! Wow!
Look at this logo, what could it say? Check it out!
With respect! With respect! With respect!
I know, I'm way too cute if we matched, right?
Right!
But maybe we'll just go run...
...and we'll let you entertain the Ruffians?
Yeah, okay! Entertain them!
Okay, you can do it! I got this!
They won't bite! They won't bite!
Ruffians! Welcome to Mori Calliope's
super special splits challenge segment! 行くぞ！
super special splits challenge segment! Let's go!
できない… I can't! I'm sorry! I can't do it!
I can't... I can't! I'm sorry! I can't do it!
I did my best!
Matching, matching! Sajisuji!
And now, that's right, we're matching!
Matching! Twins! Triplets!
Tripling! Tripleting!
Tripleting! Wow! That has a nice ring to it.
This next song is one that FuwaMoco...
...we wanted to sing with you for such a long time!
Something nostalgic, and you'll see why.
There's some rap in there as well!
But it's also very cute, right?
次歌う曲はカリ先輩と一緒に...
The next song is a song I've wanted...
ずっと歌いたかった大好きな曲ですね！
...to sing with Calli-senpai for a long time!
It's both cute, it's cool!
Yeah, but I think it shares an important part...
...to be proud of what you like, right?
Being proud and strong about what you like!
Your 'likes'!
Whether they be games, anime...
...idols, figures, or maybe even VTubers!
Nice harmony there.
Life is more fun when you're true to yourself.
Definitely! Yeah! I agree!
So we're gonna sing this song for you, okay?
Let's do the title call together! Yes!
聴いてください！ Like! Like! Like!
Please listen! Like! Like! Like!
Comic, I Like it!
Music, I Like it!
Game, I Like it!
Animation, I Like it!
Figure, I Like it!
Movie, I Like it!
Wonder, I Like it!
Hobby, I Like it!
go go go go go go go go
do you like it?
I Like it!
go go go go go go go go
do you like it? I Like it!
人生楽しんだもん勝ちの裏技
The secret to winning at life is enjoying it.
好きなもの好きって言ったらそれスーパーノヴァ
Saying you like what you like is a supernova.
快感中枢促進マックスのオーバーフロー
Promoting pleasure center to max overflow!
マジックマジック... 時空は一生でしょう
Magic, magic... Time and space is forever.
今すぐ Let's mix up!
Right now, Let's mix up!
I Like it! I Like it!
スキになれば
If you come to like it,
きっと全てがカラフルで
surely everything will be colorful.
Lucky! Lucky!
星屑さえ
Even the stardust...
光る宝物さ
...is a shining treasure!
I Like it! I Like it!
キミに合えた
I was able to meet you.
やっと今日からヨロシクね
Finally, from today, nice to meet you.
ホラ キラキラ
Look, sparkling!
夢みたい
Like a dream.
早く抱きしめたい
I want to hold you soon.
あれもこれも欲しくて 神様に祈ってる
I want this and that, I'm praying to God.
好きで好きでしょうがない
I love it, I love it, I can't help it!
次は何にしようかな
What should we do next?
歩く わるい 止まる わるい 飛ばす言葉 Like! Like! Like!
Walk, bad; stop, bad; I'll let the words fly, Like! Like! Like!
360度 パノラマ全方向 大好きの陣
360-degree panorama, in all directions—it's the love camp!
何が一つでもいいから のめり込める自分のアイテム
If there's even one thing you can lose yourself in, it's your own item
Like a superstar, fly 'em man 無敵キャンディ 他大体来世
Like a superstar, fly 'em man; invincible candy, the rest for the next life
望んでる彼もきっと 現世が愛おしくなるはずなのさ
Surely even the guy who's wishing will find this world precious
なろうとしてなるもんじゃない 人生楽しんでいこうじゃない
It's not something you force yourself into; let's just enjoy life!
自分に素直であれ
Be true to yourself
Spotlight 僕らを照らせ
Spotlight, shine on us
今日も愛を叫ぶだけだ Get down!
Today, I'll just scream my love! Get down!
Sing along a song for you!
I Like It! I Like It! 手を伸ばせば
I Like It! I Like It! If I reach out my hand
きっと全てがミラクルで
Surely everything will be a miracle
Happy! Happy! 日常でさえ
Happy! Happy! Even in daily life
夢の物語さ
It's a dream story
I Like It! I Like It! キミに会えた
I Like It! I Like It! I met you
ずっと離さないでいてね
Don't ever let go
ほらキラキラ虹みたい
Look, like a sparkling rainbow
世界はまわりだす
The world starts to spin
ガシャガシャ どこどこ ヤーヤーヤー パワー！
Splish-splash, everywhere, yaa yaa yaa! Power!
好き好き好きで勝負大 糧に得たいこの感情
Love, love, love—a big showdown, I want to fuel this feeling
歯止めと最先端 真剣勝負
The brakes and the cutting edge, a serious fight
ためらわないのがいいんでしょ？
It's better not to hesitate, right?
そう 恋も悶々と実験
Yes, love is a restless experiment
でもそれが僕の等身大
But that's my true size
Dash飛ばせ 世界を確認
Dash and fly, confirm the world
いわゆる一つの萌要素
A so-called 'moe' element
素直になれたなら Happy Days
If you can be honest, Happy Days
I Like It! I Like It! 好きになれば
I Like It! I Like It! If you fall in love
きっと全てがカラフルで
Surely everything will be colorful
Lucky! Lucky! 星屑さえ
Lucky! Lucky! Even the stardust
光る宝物さ
Is a shining treasure
I Like It! I Like It! キミに会えた
I Like It! I Like It! I met you
やっと今日からよろしくね
Finally, from today, nice to meet you
ほらキラキラ夢みたい
Look, like a sparkling dream
早く抱きしめたい
I want to hug you soon
I Like It! I Like It! 手を伸ばせば
I Like It! I Like It! If I reach out my hand
きっと全てがミラクルで
Surely everything will be a miracle
Happy! Happy! 日常でさえ
Happy! Happy! Even in daily life
ユメノモノガタリ
A dream story
I Like It! I Like It! キミに会えた
I Like It! I Like It! I met you
ずっと離さないでいてね
Don't ever let go
ほらキラキラ虹みたい
Look, like a sparkling rainbow
世界はまわりだす
The world starts to spin
How's it so fun!
That was so fun!
I Like FuwaMoco!
I love FuwaMoco!
Bye bye Bau Bau!
Please listen to our next song, Je t'aime ★ Je t'aime!
街角に並ぶ
At the corner of the town
映画のポスター
In the cinema poster
もうこの街にも
Already in this town too
秋とはきっとは
Autumn is surely coming
夕焼けの向こうに
Beyond the dusk
ため息を返す
I return a sigh
キャンセルしないで
Don't cancel it
Mon Amour pour toi
My love for you
ハートのポケットに
In my heart's pocket
隠した写真
Is a hidden photo
誰にも知らない 本気の恋
A serious love that nobody knows
神様は気づいてる
God has noticed it
Je t'aime ★ Je t'aime
I love you, I love you
叶わない夢なんて見たくないわ
I don't want to see a dream that won't come true
でもロマンス目覚めてゆく
But the romance awakes
“愛してるわ”
“I love you”
クレープに描く
I draw on a crepe
愛の傘の下で
Under the umbrella of love
止まぬ雨の音
The sound of the endless rain
Je t'aime ★ Je t'aime
I love you, I love you
AZKi先輩！アキロゼ先輩！
AZKi-senpai! AkiRose-senpai!
わあー！いらっしゃいませー！
Wow! Welcome!
ハッピーバースデー！フワモコ！
Happy Birthday, FUWAMOCO!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
それでは聴いてください、『DISCOTHEQUE』！
Now please listen to 'DISCOTHEQUE'!
Chu! Chu!
DISCOTHEQUE!
One, Two, Three, Four!
鳴り止まない　Love song
The Love Song that won't stop ringing,
もっと聴かせて　My heart
let my heart hear more of it.
揺れる　踊る　Step
Swaying, dancing steps,
終わらないで　Discotheque
don't ever let this Discotheque end.
キラキラ　光る　Mirrored ball
The glittering, shining mirrored ball,
夢の中へ　Escorting
is escorting us into a dream.
恋の魔法に　かかりそうさ
I feel like I'm falling under a love spell,
今夜は二人で　Dance
let's dance together tonight.
Chu! Chu!
DISCOTHEQUE!
アキ・ローゼ先輩と あずき先輩は
Aki-rose senpai and AZKi senpai...
とっても魅力的な お姉様たちなので
...are such charming big sisters,
あら
Oh my.
そうなんですか?
Is that so?
なのでこの曲で行こうかなと 思いました
So we thought we'd go with this song.
あらあら
Oh my, oh my.
ちょっとね、日も暮れてますし
The sun is setting a bit too.
確かに。夕方で ちょっとロマンチックになりましたね
Indeed. It's evening, it's become a bit romantic.
実はちょっぴりセクシーかも?
Actually, maybe a little sexy?
セクシーかも?
Maybe sexy?
セクシーな曲?
A sexy song?
歌ったことある?
Have you sung it before?
お願いしたことあったっけ?
Did we request it?
アキ・ローゼ先輩、
Aki-rose senpai...
この曲を歌う前に少しあの
...before we sing this song, could you...
セクシーなウォームアップを 教えて頂いてもいいですか?
...teach us a little sexy warm-up?
いいですよ!
Of course!
セクシーウォームアップ! オッケー!
Sexy warm-up! Okay!
じゃあ、まずセクシーだ体を 作るために
So first, to make a sexy body,
自分の体を撫でて
stroke your own body.
撫でて! 撫でて!
Stroke it! Stroke it!
頭撫でて。足から、足から、撫で撫で
Stroke your head. From the legs, stroke stroke.
撫でて。やってみて、やってみて
Stroke it. Try it, try it.
撫でて。アキ・ローゼ先輩みたいに
Stroke it. Like Aki-rose senpai.
あ、もこちゃんいいよ、オッケー!
Ah, Moco-chan, nice, okay!
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ!
Nice, nice, nice!
ああ、セクシー撫で撫で、セクシーだわ
Ah, sexy stroking, so sexy.
おおー、セクシー!
Ohhh, sexy!
撫で撫でセクシーだわ
Stroking is so sexy.
もこちゃん、もう一回!
Moco-chan, one more time!
ちょっと違うかな?
Maybe a bit different?
あずきちゃんもなんかセクシー だけど可愛い感じました
AZKi-chan is also sexy, but I felt some cuteness.
えー、そうですか?
Eh, is that so?
やっぱこうやって... こう?
After all, like this... Like this?
お尻とか
Like the hips.
尻尾、尻尾も撫で撫で、尻尾フリフリ
Tail, stroke the tail too, wag wag.
尻尾フリフリ。もこちゃん尻尾フリフリ
Tail wag wag. Moco-chan, tail wag wag.
ウォームアップ! ウォームアップ!
Warm-up! Warm-up!
オッケーオッケー! いいんじゃない?
Okay, okay! Isn't it good?
いいよいいよ、マスターできた?
Nice, nice, did you master it?
じゃあ、いい感じになりましたね
Well, it's feeling good now.
はい、次の曲行きましょうか!
Yes, shall we go to the next song?
じゃあ、聴いてください!
Then, please listen!
DISCOTHEQUE!
チュルチュルチュル パヤッパ
Churu Churu Churu Payappa
DISCOTHEQUE
SWEETIE DARLIN' 踊りましょう
SWEETIE DARLIN', let's dance
弾ける BEAUTY LADY
Sparkling BEAUTY LADY
生まれ変わって 甘い夢
Reborn into a sweet dream
そっと
Gently...
彩りたいの
...I want to color it.
潤ませる唇
Moisturizing lips
ピンク色の艶めくネイル
Pink, glossy nails
ガラスの向こう側に
On the other side of the glass
映る素顔 シュールな瞳
Reflected face, surreal eyes
君だけに そう 見せていたい
I want to show only you, yes
心の中 瞳の奥
Inside the heart, deep in the eyes
そばにいてほしいよ
I want you by my side
月のミラーボール 照らされて
Illuminated by the moon's mirror ball
MY DARLIN' ねえ ヴィヴィッドな
MY DARLIN', hey, let's have a...
恋しましょう
...vivid love.
弾ける SEXY BEAUTY
Sparkling SEXY BEAUTY
生まれ変わって 甘い夢
Reborn into a sweet dream
そっと 彩る MY LOVE
Gently coloring MY LOVE
ほら
Look...
世界は変わる
...the world changes.
チュルチュルチュル パヤッパ
Churu Churu Churu Payappa
SEXY BEAUTY チュルチュル...
SEXY BEAUTY, Churu Churu...
パヤッパ
...Payappa.
ドラマティックな 予感に包まれて
Enveloped in a dramatic premonition
褪せない デジャヴ 見つめ続けたくて
The unfading déjà vu, I want to keep staring
カラフルな シーン ストーリー
Colorful scene story
心深く 刻み込む
Carving deep into the heart
小さな闇が 訪れても
Even if a small darkness visits
恋の呪文 唱えたなら
If I chant the love spell
きっと 果てない空
Surely the endless sky
星屑のシャワーが 降り注ぐ
A shower of stardust falls down
だから HAPPY STATION 目指してゆこう
So let's aim for the HAPPY STATION
50/50 合わせて
Matching 50/50
100% 以上の愛
More than 100% love
揺るぎない 恋がここにあると
A steady love is right here
私を想ってる
You're thinking of me
チュルチュルチュル パヤッパ
Churu Churu Churu Payappa
君に ありのまま
To you, just as I am
好きでいてほしいと
I want you to love me
願いわくば
If I were to wish
素敵なら
If it's wonderful
ねえマイダーリン 一緒に 踊りましょう
Hey my darling, let's dance together
SECRET NIGHT 素敵な
A wonderful SECRET NIGHT
波にさらわれて この衣装
Swept away by the waves, this costume
二人のハート 惹かれあわせて
Let our two hearts be drawn together
ねえマイダーリンは ビビッドな恋しましょう
Hey my darling, let's have a vivid love
はじけてる SEXY BEAUTY
Bursting SEXY BEAUTY
生まれ変わって 甘い夢
Reborn into a sweet dream
そっと彩る MY LOVE ほら
Gently coloring my love, look
世界は変わる
The world will change
CHURU CHURU CHURU PAPAPA
燃え尽きるわ この恋 多分
I'll probably burn out, this love
どんな結末が来ようと
No matter what conclusion comes
覚悟してる
I'm prepared
余裕なんて ほとんどない
I have almost no leeway
必死で しがみついてるだけ
I'm just desperately clinging on
あなたの目 優しく抱き寄せる腕
Your eyes, the arms that gently pull me close
すべてが すべてが 初めての
Everything, everything is for the first time
One For Last Night
Kiss me
離さないで
Don't let me go
Kiss me
自然なままで
Just as you are
この不安も 拭いとって ねえ...
Wipe away this anxiety too, hey...
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey hey hey hey hey hey hey hey
Touch me
その指先
Those fingertips
Touch me
その眼差しで
With that look in your eyes
この私を 包み込んで Please...
Embrace me, please...
Please Please Please Please Please Please
愛してる
I love you
蘇るわ 昨日のこと
Yesterday's events come back to me
あんなに心が 揺れたの
My heart wavered so much
初めてだもん
Because it's the first time
寂しすぎて 時々怖い
It's so lonely, sometimes I'm scared
二人でいられない この時が
These times when we can't be together
雨の朝 暖かな部屋でコーヒー
A rainy morning, coffee in a warm room
大人のふりから
From pretending to be an adult
本物の大人になりそう
I feel like I'm becoming a real adult
Kiss me
危険なほど
To a dangerous degree
Kiss me
甘いくちづけ
A sweet kiss
この願いを 全部叶えて ねえ...
Grant all these wishes, hey...
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey hey hey hey hey hey hey hey
Knock me
その吐息で
With that breath
Knock me
ドアを叩いて
Knock on the door
この私を 安心させて Please...
Make me feel at ease, please...
Please Please Please Please Please Please
愛してる
I love you
Kiss me 危険なほど
Kiss me, dangerously so
Kiss me 甘いくちづけ
Kiss me, a sweet kiss
こんな願いを 全部かなえて
Grant all of these wishes
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ...
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
Knock me その魂で
Knock me, with that soul
Knock me 窓を叩いて
Knock me, knock on the window
こんな私を 安心させて
Make me feel at ease
Please Please Please Please...
愛してる
I love you
Wappy!
Are you ready?
Let's go!
Please enjoy Triangle Dreamer!
Day by day 日に日に募るの乙女心
Day by day, the maiden's heart grows stronger
おんなじクラス斜め前のおとなしい人
The quiet boy in the seat diagonally in front of me
カッコ良くはない だけど優しい
He isn't cool, but he's kind
いつも頼れる彼
He's always the one I can rely on
After school 恋愛相談の帰り道
After school, on the way home from talking about love
なんだって話せる親友の女の子
My best friend, who I can tell anything to
スポーツ万能 勉強もできて
She's good at sports, smart at studies
女子力MAXです
And has maximum feminine charm
どこにでもある よくあること
It happens everywhere, the usual thing
急に彼女が
Suddenly, she said:
「あのね、実は私好きな人が…」
"You know, actually, I have a crush on someone..."
ちょ、マジで!?
Wait, seriously!?
三角形、三角形の恋はきまぐれ
A triangle, a triangle love, so fickle
一瞬で、一瞬で崩れるバランス
In an instant, in an instant, the balance collapses
ベタな漫画みたいなフラグ
A flag like in a bad manga
まさかね自分か立っちゃうなんて
I never thought I'd be the one standing there
残念すぎます！
What a disappointment!
三角形、三角形の恋は不安定
A triangle, a triangle love is unstable
なんちゃって、なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
It's not a category you can just ignore
恋と友情 ゆらゆらめいて
Love and friendship, swaying, swaying
なんか青春しちゃいます
It feels like youth
わたし困っちゃいます
I'm in trouble
乾杯です
It's a toast
お似合いすぎるわ 手に負えない
You suit each other too well, I can't handle it
悔しいけど どっかそんなんじゃなくて 本心
Frustrating, but somewhere that's not it, it's my heart
っていうか すでに応援モード
In fact, I'm already in support mode
むしろ 清々しい
Rather, it's refreshing
だけど彼女は 不思議な顔
But she has a puzzled look on her face
真剣な目で
With serious eyes
「そうじゃなくて私 あなたが好き。ごめん」
"Not that, I like you. Sorry."
ちょ、マジで!?
Wait, seriously!?
三角形、三角形の恋はきまぐれ
A triangle, a triangle love, so fickle
一瞬で、一瞬で崩れるバランス
In an instant, in an instant, the balance collapses
わたし あなた 彼女とわたし
Me, you, her and me
超絶！複雑！百合！展開は想定外です！
Super! Complex! Yuri! The development is unexpected!
三角形、三角形の恋は不安定
A triangle, a triangle love is unstable
なんちゃって、なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
It's not a category you can just ignore
解けないパズル 与えたもうた
An unsolvable puzzle has been granted to us
神よ 恨んじゃいます
God, I'm going to resent you
私 悩んじゃいます
I'm worrying myself over this
あー、もうすごいヤバイ
Ah, this is really bad!
好きだよ 好きだけど でもそういう意味じゃなくって
I like her! I do, but not in THAT way!
だって女の子同士だし
I mean, we're both girls...
ねえ神様 どうしたらいいの？
Oh God, what should I do?
私 どうしたいの？
What do I WANT to do?
ヘルプミー！
Help me!
なんか変だ 愛に国境も年もち性別も関係ない
It's weird. Love knows no borders, age, or gender.
けど けど けど
But, but, but...
三角形 三角形の恋はきまぐれ
Triangle... a triangle love is fickle.
一瞬で 一瞬でくずれるバランス
In a flash, in a flash the balance crumbles.
普通の恋 夢みてたのに
Even though I dreamed of a normal love...
ノーマル設定のわたしじゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます
For my normal settings, this is a bit too much of a 'kusoge'.
三角形 三角形の恋は不安定
Triangle... a triangle love is unstable.
なんちゃって なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
It's a category that 'just kidding' won't fix.
彼女のこと 好きになれたなら
If only I could fall in love with her...
なんて妄想しちゃいます 私どかしてます
I'm having such delusions. Something's wrong with me!
いくよー！
Here we go!
Bau bau! Thank you Ruffians!
That was so much fun!
Yeah! Although, I got a bit dizzy though.
Yeah, from the bubble and then changing so quickly.
But it was so fun!
Yeah, you know, the bubble dash was a little bit silly.
But did we surprise you?
And we got to see your smiles even more close up than usual!
Wow! Those last two songs we sang were 'Kiss me! Choose me!' together with Alvin...
And 'Triangle Dreamer'!
With Miki-senpai, Mio-senpai, and Subaru-senpai!
What'd you think, Ruffians?
Kiss me! Choose me! is a song that I've always wanted to sing together with Alvin!
It's a little bit more sexy... a bit sexy song, right?
Yeah! And 'Triangle Dreamer'! The best of idol songs!
そう、ゆり展開が急すぎて、え、ラフィアンズまだ生きてる？
Yeah, that yuri development was so sudden. Are you Ruffians still alive?
え？生きてる？
Huh? Are you alive?
Yeah, Bau bau! Our senpai were so cute and wow!
And then crowd surfing at the bubble!
It was the best! A lot of firsts this year, right?
Yeah! Wow, we have a tiny, tiny announcement!
Huh? You know, as FUWAMOCO, it's our birthday, right? Our birthday!
And so, we have something we'd like to share with you!
Ready? Okay! One, two...
ドーン！
Bam!
It's time to celebrate both of our birthdays...
...with our FUWAMOCO 2026 Birthday Merch!
ふわもこの生誕グッズ紹介、始まるよ！
The introduction for FUWAMOCO's birthday merch starts now!
First, we became fluffy and fuzzy idols with the Fuwa Fuwa Idol Fuwawa...
...and Moco Moco Idol Mococo acrylic stands! Drawn by our mama, Icomochi-mama!
They're rather big compared to regular acrylic stands, so we think they'd be a great addition to your collection!
大きめサイズで可愛いアイドルのふわもこアクリルスタンド！
A large-sized, cute idol FUWAMOCO acrylic stand!
Next, we have the silly Ehehe Angel and Hoeh?! Devil rubber figurines!
Win-our palm-sized figures, perfect for displaying on your desk!
ハロウィン衣装のふわもこが手のひらサイズのラバーマスコットになったよ！
FUWAMOCO in Halloween outfits have become palm-sized rubber mascots!
This one is big!
We finally have FUWAMOCO plushies in our Out-and-About casual outfits!
But this time, we also speak in your houses!
It's the Yappy Puppy Fuwawa/Mococo Sounds Plushie!
They'll be the same size as our Friends with You plushies, so you can display them together!
おしゃべりパピーMOCOCOぬいぐるみ
Talking Puppy MOCOCO Plushie
ギュッとすると、色々喋るよ！
It'll say various things if you give it a squeeze!
どんなボイスが出るか、お楽しみに！
Look forward to hearing what voices it has!
We have the Fuwawa to GO Finger Puppet!
They come with an extra Ruffians kigurumi costume to dress them up and bring them everywhere!
FUWAWA to GO 指パペット
FUWAWA to GO Finger Puppet
どこでも一緒に連れていけるサイズで、着せ替えラフィアンズ衣装もありよ！
Take it anywhere! Comes with a Ruffians costume!
Finally, we have two different ASMR voice packs: "Back from a Fluffy Date" with Fuwawa...
...and "Sweet and Fuzzy Needy Puppy" from Mococo!
ASMRボイスは、英語と日本語、両方で収録してます！
ASMR voices are recorded in English and Japanese!
They make our hearts beat so fast!
Be ready to blush when you take a listen to them!
The merch is separated into two sets: Fuwawa's Birthday Merch and Mococo's Birthday Merch.
Full sets come with bonuses, including a Cheki-style card with a special bonus voice!
グッズはフワワセットとモココセットに分かれています。
The merch is split into a Fuwawa set and a Mococo set.
セットごとにチェキ風カードと特典ボイスが付きます。
Each set comes with a Cheki-style card and bonus voice.
The regular version will have a foil-stamped replica signature and message!
数量限定セットは直筆サイン入りだよ！
The limited edition set comes with a handwritten signature!
We put lots of love into each signature, so we hope you look forward to it!
たくさん愛情込めてサイン書きますね！
We'll put lots of love into writing the signatures!
Check out the hololive official shop and look for the link in the description or comments!
ぜひホロライブ公式ショップをチェックしてください！
Please check out the hololive official shop!
バウバウ！
Bau Bau!
What did you think of our birthday merch? Pretty cute, huh?
Reservations go on sale right after the birthday live ends, so don't forget!
生誕のグッズの予約はこの後開始しますので、
Reservations for the birthday merch will start after this,
お忘れずにチェックしてください！
so please don't forget to check them out!
Use the link below or on the side here! Don't forget, okay?
We put a lot of love into it, and Ikomochi-mama too!
Right after this ends, time to go, go, go!
Go buy it!
Well, we performed a lot of special collab songs with our dear Senpai...
...but there's still one mystery guest we haven't met yet, right?
そう！まだ会ってない謎のゲストが一人いるんだよ！
Right! There's still one mystery guest we haven't met yet!
Well, shall we give the Ruffians a hint?
Ruffians are curious, why?
コブダイ？
Napoleonfish?
ヤゴーさん？
Yago-san?
That's a good guess maybe, but... well, see, huh?
Maybe you should get ready, because, you know...
...they aren't quite as bad as Pero, but they can get pretty nasty!
Mococo-chan, don't be rude to our next guest, okay?
Especially before calling them out!
We'll see!
Well, let's get them out here then! Who could it be?
Okay! せーの！どうぞー！
Okay! One, two! Come on out!
わわわわわ！きたしんよ！きたしんよ！
Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa! He's here-shun! He's here-shun!
バッキュン！
Bakkyun!
チュッチュ！
Chu-chu!
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourself!
クロちゃんです！わわわわわー！
I'm Kuro-chan! Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa!
日本の芸人 安田大サーカス クロちゃん
Japanese Comedian Yasuda Dai Circus Kuro-chan
初めまして！
Nice to meet you!
チワワじゃないよ！フワワだよ！
I'm not a Chihuahua! I'm Fuwawa!
フワワじゃないよ！モココだよ！
I'm not Fuwawa! I'm Mococo!
2人合わせて、フワモコです！
Together, we are FuwaMoco!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
フワモコのわちゃわちゃバースデーフェスティバルに来てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for coming to FuwaMoco's Birthday Festival!
ハッピーバースデーだしんよ！フワモコ！
Happy Birthday-shun, FuwaMoco!
いいしんねー！
It's great-shun!
視聴者のラフィアンズはたくさんいると思いますけど、
I'm sure many Ruffians are watching,
クロちゃんがどんな人なのか説明してもらえますか？
but could you explain who you are, Kuro-chan?
自分ですんの？それ。
I have to do it myself?
Introduction!
わかったしんよ。海外の人も見てますもんね。
Got it-shun. Overseas people are watching too.
海外の人もわかる自己紹介しますからね。
I'll do an intro they can understand.
Nice to meet you, chu, chu, chu, chu, tulip!
え、クロちゃんは…チューリップ？
Um, Kuro-chan is... a tulip?
チューリップ、ノー、ノー、ノー！
Tulip, no, no, no!
ちゃんとまだわからないかもしれないから。
They might not understand yet.
安田大サーカスっていうトリオを組んでる芸人さんで、
I'm a comedian in a trio called Yasuda Dai Circus,
豆柴の大群のプロデューサーや作詞もしてます、クロちゃんです！
and producer for Mameshiba no Taigun. I'm Kuro-chan!
おー！バウバウ！
Oh! Bau Bau!
じゃあ今回は英語でお願いします！
Now, in English please!
In English?
僕が？ 自分？
Me? Myself?
えー、そんなこと急に言われたら… It's shy! Flower!
Uh, if you say that all of a sudden... It's shy! Flower!
言い訳はなし！
No excuses!
ねえ、聞いてる人の話？
Hey, are you listening to me?
ねえ。いや、頑張って。一生懸命…
Hey. No, do your best. Hard work...
Famous comedian.
ああ、コメディアン。
Oh, comedian.
あとアイドルプロデューサー。
And an idol producer.
やってるしんよ！
I'm doing it!
おお、できる…
Oh, he can...
凄ーい！
Amazing!
クロちゃんテレビでよく見てるけど…
I see Kuro-chan on TV a lot...
ちょっとふわもこのペットのペロちゃんと…
But he's a bit like Fuwamoco's pet Pero-chan...
えっと、ちょっと似てるところが…
Um, there are some similar parts...
たくさんあるね。
Quite a lot.
お前…え？
You... what?
ちょっと後ろの家見てください。見えますか？
Look at the house in the back. Can you see it?
あ、そうするとペロです。ペロ。
Ah, and then there's Pero. Pero.
ちょっと待って。丸いところが似てるだけじゃない？
Wait. Is it just the round part that's similar?
ねえ！そうじゃない？
Hey! Isn't that right?
ホントに？うん。
Really? Yeah.
えっと、クロちゃんと似てるところは…
Um, the parts that are similar to Kuro-chan are...
嘘つきで…
He's a liar...
え！？
What!?
女の子好きで…
He likes girls...
あらやだ！やらしい！
Oh my! How lewd!
うん。
Yeah.
だからね、見た目で騙されないで。
So, don't be fooled by appearances.
クロちゃんはそんなんで大丈夫なの？言われて。
Is Kuro-chan okay being told that?
いや、ひどい。悲しくなってきた。
No, that's cruel. I'm getting sad.
えーん、えーん、えーん。
Waaah, waaah, waaah.
泣いちゃった！
He's crying!
えーん、ぽいぽいえーん。
Waaah, poipoi waaah.
全然人のギャグを聴かないよね、君たちは。
You guys don't listen to other people's gags at all, do you?
えへへ。
Ehehe.
できれば…
If possible...
クロちゃんはペロの友達に…
Would Kuro-chan become Pero's friend...
なってくれませんか？
Won't you?
ふわもこの友達じゃなくてペロの友達なの？
Not Fuwamoco's friend, but Pero's friend?
あ、ふわもこはクロちゃんと友達になりたくないから…
Ah, because Fuwamoco doesn't want to be friends with Kuro-chan...
おかしくない、それ？
Isn't that strange?
いやいやいや、気持ち悪いから！
No, no, no, because it's gross!
いや、気持ち悪くない。マニアには受ける！
No, it's not gross. Maniacs will love it!
いや、違う。
No, that's wrong.
ふわもこ、気持ち悪い、やっぱり。
Fuwamoco thinks it's gross after all.
でも、モコちゃん。
But, Moco-chan.
ちょっとやりすぎですよ。失礼です。
You're overdoing it a bit. It's rude.
え？
What?
いや、もしペロと仲良くなってほしいんだったら…
No, if you want me to get along with Pero...
ふわもこちゃん、クロちゃんに可愛らしく頼んだほうがいいんじゃない？
Fuwamoco-chan, shouldn't you ask Kuro-chan more cutely?
はぁ！？
Hah!?
ノー！
No!
え、ノー！？ノー！？
Eh, no!? No!?
しっかりとした否定。ノー。
A firm denial. No.
ま、けどペロ可愛いから仲良くなってもいいと思ってるよ。
Well, but Pero is cute, so I think it's okay to get along.
あ、嬉しい、嬉しい、嬉しい。
Ah, I'm happy, happy, happy.
可愛くないけど、なんか仲良くなってくれたら嬉しいかな。
He's not cute, but I'd be happy if you got along.
感情が、感情がいろいろありすぎなのよ、本当に。
You have too many, too many different emotions, really.
はい。
Yes.
まあまあ。クロちゃんって芸人さんだけど…
Well, well. Kuro-chan is a comedian, but...
アイドルになりたいんですよね？ねえ。
You want to be an idol, right? Right.
そう、元々アイドルになろうと思ったのに…
Yes, I originally intended to become an idol...
騙されて芸人にさせられたから…
But I was tricked into becoming a comedian...
アイドルは本当に夢、ドリーム。
So being an idol is really a dream, a dream.
あー、なんか悲しいな。
Ah, that's kind of sad.
可哀想。
Poor thing.
でもドリームって大事ですから。
But dreams are important.
大事。うん。
Important. Yeah.
そう、で、まあクロちゃんのドリームはアイドルなんだから…
Right, and since Kuro-chan's dream is being an idol...
もうせっかく、一緒に歌ってくれませんか？
Won't you sing with us since you're here?
あー！
Ah!
いいしんよ、いいしんよ！オッケーだしんよ。
It's okay, it's okay! It's okay!
えっと、踊れるのね、あの曲。
Um, you can dance to that song, right?
え、何？
Eh, what?
うん、この曲。次の曲ね。
Yeah, this song. The next song.
あの、ハードル上げないで。
Um, don't raise the hurdles.
大丈夫でしょ、ね？
It'll be fine, right?
アイドルのプロデュースもやってるし。
You're also producing idols.
そうそう。
Right, right.
実力見せてよ。
Show us your skills.
見せて！
Show us!
オッケーだしんよ、行くしんよ、行くしんよ。
It's okay, let's go, let's go.
オッケー！うん。
Okay! Yeah.
じゃあ、凄く可愛い曲を一緒に歌いましょう。
Then, let's sing a very cute song together.
え、何の曲だ？楽しみ。
Eh, what song is it? I'm looking forward to it.
オッケー。
Okay.
はぁ。
Hah.
じゃあ、一緒にタイトルコールしましょうね。
Then, let's do the title call together.
ねえ。
Right.
せーの！
One, two...
ちゅ、多様性。
Chu, Tayousei.
あ、多様性なの！？
Ah, it's Tayousei!?
ちゅ、多様性。
Chu, Tayousei.
我愛你 酔いが覚めない
Wo ai ni, the intoxication won't wear off
我愛你 恋が覚めない
Wo ai ni, the love won't wake up
我愛你 御生様の成れ果てして
Wo ai ni, the result of being too used to this life
無問題 炸裂してみて無問題
No problem, try bursting, no problem
Hold me tight トラウマの味
Hold me tight, the taste of trauma
猛反対 お手々座りでハイ❤報酬
Strong opposition, sit down and say 'yes' for a reward
喉の奥がチュンチュンチュン
Deep in the throat, it's 'chun-chun-chun'
僕はドクンドクン
I am 'dokun-dokun'
鼓動で孤独消してみてよ
Try erasing the loneliness with the heartbeat
愛も恋も独占して
Monopolize both love and romance
僕を独占して
Monopolize me
このままチュードクになるまでチュウしよう
Let's kiss until we become 'chu-doku' (addicted)
Get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
Get get get on! Get get get get on chu!
熱く とろけるくらいに溢れた気持ちが
Feelings overflowing so much they melt
たまらないでしょ
It's irresistible, isn't it?
Get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
Get get get on! Get get get get on chu!
我愛你 無問題
Wo ai ni, no problem
Get get get on chu!
ポン・チー・カン 勝負はいつもトンチンカン
Pon, chi, kan, the game is always absurd
僕に言わせりゃチンプンカンプン
If you ask me, it's all gibberish
こんな最後はロンでしょ？
An ending like this must be a 'ron', right?
もう何回？殺られればいい
How many more times? It's fine to be killed
Oh, One night 忘れられない
Oh, one night, I can't forget
終わんないで
Don't end it...
トキメキへん愛予習
...prep for the heart-pounding forbidden love.
喉の奥がチクンチクン
My throat is tingling.
僕はドクンドクン
My heart is thumping.
心臓ごと引きずり出してみてよ
Try dragging my whole heart out.
気持ちいいね面倒くさいけど
It feels good, though it's a hassle.
やっぱ照れくさいけど
It's embarrassing, though.
死ぬまで忘れられないチューしよ
Let's have a kiss we'll never forget until we die.
いかれた俺はゾンビで溢れる
The crazy me is overflowing with zombies.
君は僕に恋してる
You are in love with me.
ゾクゾク胸に繋がる
Connecting to your thumping chest...
動物を引きなよ
...pull the animals.
Bet on chu!
本気で狂えるくらいの美しさが
A beauty so great it could truly drive you crazy...
美しいでしょ
...is beautiful, isn't it?
Get on chu!
ポン・チー・カン 終わんない
Pon, Chii, Kan! It won't end!
Get get get on chu!
我愛你 無問題
I love you, no problem.
Get get get on chu!
わあ、やったー！うまくいったしんよー！
Wow, we did it! It went well, shin!
ありがとう！よかった！
Thank you! I'm so glad!
頑張ったね、クロちゃん！
You did your best, Kurochan!
楽しかった、ありがとう！
That was fun, thank you!
よかったー！
I'm so happy!
え、ちょっとね、さよならする前に...
Um, before we say goodbye...
なに？
What?
えっと、一個お願いしてもいいですか？
Um, can I ask one favor?
一個だけだしんよー！
Just one, shin!
一個だけじゃあ...
Then just one...
えっと、フワモコは魔界の番犬で、
Well, FuwaMoco are guard dogs from the Underworld,
バウバウよく言ってるんですけど...
and we say 'Bau Bau' a lot...
うんうん
Yeah, yeah.
クロちゃん、カメラに向かって
Kurochan, could you look at the camera
フワモコのように可愛いバウバウしてもらえますか？
and do a cute 'Bau Bau' like FuwaMoco?
えー、できるかしん...
Eh, I wonder if I can...
いくしんよー！
Here I go, shin!
バウバウ！
Bau Bau!
えー、バウ！それがベスト？
Eh, Bau! Was that your best?
えー、もう一回！もっとやってー！
Eh, one more time! Do it more!
バウバウ！
Bau Bau!
可愛いかな？
Was it cute?
実は、もう一個やりたいことがあるんですけど...
Actually, there's one more thing I want to do...
なに？
What?
さっきもやりましたけど、フワモコは
We did it earlier, but FuwaMoco
いつもやってる自己紹介があって...
has a self-introduction we always do...
できれば、三人で一緒にやりたいです！
If possible, I'd like the three of us to do it together!
あ、あれ可愛かったからやりたいしんよー！
Oh, that was cute, so I want to do it, shin!
じゃあ、いきますよ！
Okay, here we go!
チワワじゃないよ、フワワだよ！
I'm not a Chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
ワワワワワ！フワワじゃないよ、クロちゃんどよ！
Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa! Not Fuwawa, I'm Kurochan!
え、クロちゃんじゃないよ、モココだよ！
Eh, I'm not Kurochan, I'm Mococo!
三人に合わせて、せーの、バウバウ！
Together as three, one, two, Bau Bau!
ちょっと！怒らないで！どうしたの？
Hey! Don't get mad! What's wrong?
全然違うよ、クロちゃん！
That's not it at all, Kurochan!
合ってないかな？なんなのそれ？
Was it off? What's with that?
もう嘘とかつかないよね？
You won't tell lies anymore, right?
つかないよ！
I won't!
モココパンチしちゃうよ！
Mococo will punch you!
救急車一台！
One ambulance, please!
いらないよ、もう嘘つかないで！
You don't need one, just stop lying!
バウバウ！なんでバウバウ怒るの？
Bau Bau! Why are you getting 'Bau Bau' mad?
落ち着いて、落ち着いて！
Calm down, calm down!
大丈夫、モコちゃん、大丈夫。
It's okay, Moco-chan, it's okay.
クロちゃんは、これからもみんなを
Kurochan, please continue to make everyone
いっぱい笑顔にして、素敵なアイドルになってくださいね！
smile and be a wonderful idol!
なるしんよー！
I will, shin!
バウバウ！
Bau Bau!
じゃあ、モコちゃん、最後にクロちゃんに
Then, Moco-chan, let's finish with a
ハイタッチしてお別れしようね。
high five with Kurochan and say goodbye.
仲直り、仲直りいい？
Make up, make up, okay?
仲直り？
Make up?
はい、どうぞ、ハイタッチ。
Here you go, high five.
ほらほら、仲直り、仲直り。
Come on, let's make up, make up.
でいっ！バーイ！
Dei! Bye!
ひどくない？なんなのもう！
Isn't that cruel? What the heck!
でも、フワモコちゃん、本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます！
But FuwaMoco-chan, really, Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！クロちゃん！
Thank you, Kurochan!
キュンからのバッキュン！おめでとう！ハート！
A kyun and a bang! Congratulations! Heart!
え、サンキュー！
Eh, thank you!
たまやー！
Tamaya!
かぎやー！
Kagiya!
Fireworks! Beautiful FuwaMoco fireworks!
わあ、すごい！バウバウ！
Wow, amazing! Bau Bau!
Things got really crazy though, not too sure what happened.
色々と凄すぎて分からなくなってきたかも。
So much happened that I'm starting to get confused.
But we still have one more thing, one more very exciting thing to show you!
まだまだ楽しみがあるよ！
There's still more to look forward to!
Maybe Ruff-ruffs can guess what it is?
何かなー？何かなー？
What could it be? What could it be?
FuwaMoco and our first anniversary!
We were able to release our very, very first original song, "FUWAMOCO Abura Age!"
Going to Bau-Bau!
And then for our second anniversary, we were able to release "Lifetime Showtime!"
Our original song that's been with us along this journey...
...a very special song.
And you know, for FUWAMOCO, singing and dancing is something that means so much to us!
Yeah, music!
And Ruffians, you might have heard that you'd like to hear more from us too, right?
Yeah, yeah!
What do you think? Yeah?
Well...
...our announcement is...
Drumroll!
Okay, drumroll! Yeah!
Pupupupupupupupupupupupu...
DUN!
A NEW ORIGINAL SONG!
新、新、新オリジナル曲！
A new, new, new original song!
And this song is extra special!
It's written by none other than the legendary...
...rock idol song composer, Matsukuma Kenta-san!
Who works with many famous idol groups we love!
He's also written music for the idol group...
...that Kuro-chan produces, 豆柴の大群さん！
...that Kuro-chan produces, MAMESHIBA NO TAIGUN!
But Ruffians, you might be a little bit surprised, okay?
So get ready!
Ruffians, with this song, we'd like to express our Ruffian feelings as Demon Dogs!
DEMON'S RESIDENCE.
「相棒、どこへ行こうか」
"Partner, where shall we go?"
ネオンの脇を抜け
Passing through the neon lights,
バブルガムがはじけたら let's go
When the bubblegum pops, let's go
最低な夜を潜って
Wading through the worst nights,
僕らは群れをなす
we form a pack.
「あの頃よりもマシだね」 my way
"It's better than back then," my way.
「不完全なんです」
"I am incomplete,"
首輪をつけた
wearing a collar.
良い子なんじゃもう
Being a good girl is no longer...
イヤ
...enough!
DEMON'S RESIDENCE 噛みついていけ
DEMON'S RESIDENCE, bite into it.
この街は檻のようで
This city is like a cage.
気分はどうだい 泣いているのかい
How are you feeling? Are you crying?
鎖をちぎって 叫んでいたいんだ
I want to tear off the chains and scream.
stray dogs
彼方へと 飛ぶ鳥を
The birds flying into the distance,
見上げるだけかい それでいいのかい
are you just looking up? Is that okay?
震えるなら ほら 青く
If you're trembling, look, turn blue.
「説教なんかいらない」スプレー缶振って
"I don't need a lecture," shaking a spray can.
イタズラ書きで彩る runway
Coloring the runway with graffiti.
愛情なんか coin toss
Love is like a coin toss,
誰に bet するのか
who will you bet on?
不確定要素ばかりね lonely
It's all uncertain elements, lonely.
二人でひとつと決めた
The two of us decided to be one.
あの日を忘れない Ah!!
I won't forget that day, Ah!!
DEMON'S RESIDENCE 満天の空
DEMON'S RESIDENCE, the star-filled sky.
あの星がひどく不快で
That star is terribly unpleasant.
勝利はどうだい 味がするのかい
How is victory? Does it have a taste?
鎖を噛んで 唸っていたいんだ
I want to bite the chains and growl.
stray dogs 僕ら
Stray dogs, we'll...
空さえも撃ち落として
...even shoot down the sky.
見下ろす奈落 ビルは輝く
Looking down at the abyss, the buildings shine.
LOL Now I am free!!
孤独を分け合い
Sharing loneliness,
食べた
we ate it.
あの日を忘れない
I won't forget that day.
夜を睨んだ stray dogs そうだ
Stray dogs glaring at the night, that's right.
怪物はこの世のほうさ
The monster is this world itself.
抜け出せるのかい 足は動くかい
Can you escape? Are your legs moving?
走るなら今
If you're going to run, it's now.
DEMON'S RESIDENCE stray dogs 僕ら
DEMON'S RESIDENCE, stray dogs, we...
この街を駆け抜けて行け
...run through this city.
地獄の果てに 何が見えるかい
What can you see at the edge of hell?
鎖をちぎって 叫んでいたいんだ
I want to tear off the chains and scream.
stray dogs 僕ら
Stray dogs, we...
この街は檻のようで
...this city is like a cage.
君ならどうだい 共に駆けるかい
What about you? Will you run with us?
夜明けが合図だ 行こう
The dawn is the signal, let's go.
side by side
Bau Bau!
Thank you for always being here for us, Ruffians!
Please listen to...
...side by side!
Finally we made it through
but not without some tears
With the help of friends so true
we faced all of our fears
Now we're here to celebrate
all that we have done
I can feel it's more than just a game of fate
'cause our stories have just begun
Hand in hand we're not waiting on tomorrow
From now on it's the heart that we will follow
We'll move on past the heartbreak and the sorrow
if you stay by my side
Dancing, harmonies feeding the music
as we come alive and sparks ignite
We're making memories everyday underneath
the summer sky and through the night
We're singing melodies every time we hear music
from inside as hearts collide
Bringing out the best in each other,
now we're feeling free like we're meant to be
Even though there's been rough times
when nobody wanted us
We kept going and we kept dreaming
Now we're here, we're not alone anymore
To be here together, we have smiles to protect
Come on, let's go!
Dancing, harmonies feeding the music
as we come alive and sparks ignite
We're making memories everyday underneath
the summer sky and through the night
We're singing melodies every time we hear music
from inside as hearts collide
Bringing out the best in each other,
now we're feeling free like we're meant to be
Bau Bau!
Thank you for the encore, Ruffians!
That was side by side! Bau Bau!
We're really happy to perform side by side
for you for the first time live today!
Yeah! 初披露できてとっても嬉しいです！
Yeah! We're so happy to perform it for the first time!
side by side is a song made by Aiobahn-san,
but also between FUWAMOCO!
Yeah, and us!
We know it's a song that you love a lot,
but we also do, because it's very special to us...
...since it's the ending theme for a visual novel
that we care about!
NEKOPARA!
Bau Bau!
And with this song, our dream of singing the opening
or ending theme for visual novel came true!
そう、この曲でFUWAMOCOの夢、
That's right, with this song, FUWAMOCO's dream...
美少女ゲームの主題歌を歌うことが叶いました！
...to sing a visual novel theme song has come true!
Bau Bau! Bau Bau!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
And thank you so much for joining us
for our special day again this year!
It's been a dream, Bau Bau!
And you know, it's all because of you
that we're able to be here
and do all the amazing things that we do,
so thank you!
It's sad to say, but...
This next song is our last song.
Aww...
But like all of them, it's a very special one.
You know Fuwawa and I, as demon dogs, we're here to protect your smile, right?
We'll continue to do that, protect your smile, as your idols!
And just as our fluffy and fuzzy souls too,
we'll continue to be here for thousands and thousands of demon dog years,
always remembering that, you know, every day isn't given.
Yeah, we don't take anything for granted.
And you know, when you're down, we hope that you'll remember
that we're always here cheering you on, okay?
We'll cheer you on always!
So, please listen closely to the lyrics of our last song for today.
明日も
Tomorrow,
明後日も
the day after too,
あなたが笑ってますように
I hope you're smiling.
ずっと
Always...
lala...
Thank you so much Ruffians for spending our birthday with us today!
Please think of this song whenever things are rough, and know that we'll be here.
This last song is for you: Wishful Garnet!
過去を振り返ると
When I look back at the past,
思い出す
I remember...
ガーネットの空
the garnet sky.
溢れてく
Overflowing...
光
light.
この瞳に映し出された
Reflected in these eyes,
あの日は
that day was...
美しく
beautifully...
揺れる
swaying.
What do you think?
赤く
Redly...
滲んだ
blurred...
空に
in the sky,
願いました
I made a wish.
どうかこの願い
Please, let this wish...
届けてください
reach you.
明日も
Tomorrow,
明後日も
the day after too,
あなたが笑ってますように
I hope you're smiling.
離れ離れになっても
Even if we're apart,
前を向けますように
I hope we can look forward.
あなたを
The chains...
縛る鎖を
that bind you,
わたしが壊してあげる
I will break them for you.
もう
No more...
負けないで
don't lose,
進むこと
and keep moving forward.
いつでもそばにいるから
Because I'm always by your side.
落ち込んだり
When you're depressed,
自信を無くした時だって
or when you've lost your confidence...
目の前にいてくれる
you're right there in front of me.
あなたの笑顔に
Your smile...
何度となく
has countless times...
救われた
saved me.
だから
That's why...
So I love you
挫けそうになったら
If you're about to give up,
手を伸ばして
reach out your hand.
まだ知らない明日
To a tomorrow yet unknown,
一緒に見つけよう
let's find it together.
明日も
Tomorrow,
明後日も
the day after too,
あなたを照らしていたい
I want to keep shining on you.
泣きそうになった時は
When you're about to cry,
こっち向いてほしい
I want you to look this way.
世界で
In the world,
ひとりぼっち
all alone...
そんな風に思わないで
don't think like that.
愛してくれる人はきっと
The person who loves you is surely...
いつもあなたを想ってる
always thinking of you.
la la la...
願いました
I made a wish.
どうかこの願い
Please, let this wish...
届けてください
reach you.
明日も
Tomorrow,
明後日も
the day after too,
あなたが笑ってますように
I hope you're smiling.
離れ離れになっても
Even if we're apart,
前を向けますように
I hope we can look forward.
あなたを
The chains...
縛る鎖を
that bind you,
わたしが壊してあげる
I will break them for you.
もう
No more...
負けないで
don't lose,
進むこと
and keep moving forward.
輝く空へ
Towards the shining sky.
明日も
Tomorrow,
明後日も
the day after too,
あなたが笑ってますように
I hope you're smiling.
離れ離れになっても
Even if we are separated,
前を向けますように
So that you can look forward,
あなたを縛る鎖を
The chains that bind you,
わたしが壊してあげる
I will break them for you.
もう負けないで進むこと
To keep moving forward without losing anymore.
いつでもそばに
Always by your side,
あなたのそばに
Right beside you,
わたしはいつもいるから
Because I'll always be with you.
BAU BAU!
Thank you so much for coming!
We'll see you soon
at our encore live in membership, okay?
BAU BAU!
メン限アンコールライブで待ってるよー！
See you at our encore live in membership!